Contact

rogeraleite@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rogeraleite (LinkedIn)

www.cvast.tuwien.ac.at/team/roger-leite (Company)

Top Skills

Agile Methodologies
Data Science
Algorithms

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Professional Working)

Certifications

Process Mining: Data science in Action

Publications

Visual Analytics for Fraud Detection: Focusing on Profile Analysis

Many Views Are Not Enough: Designing for Synoptic Insights in Cultural Collections

Cycle Plot Revisited: Multivariate Outlier Detection Using a Distance-Based Abstraction

Shapes of Time: Visualizing Set Changes Over Time in Cultural Heritage Collections

Network Analysis for Financial Fraud Detection

Roger A. Leite

Ph.D. in Data Visual Analytics Vienna

Summary

Ph.D. in Data Visual Analytics, Computer Scientist. 8 years working with Data Science and Visual Analytics.

My main interests include Data Science, Visual Analysis, Business Intelligence, and Agile Methodologies. During eight years of developing research, I am most proud of the wide variety of research domains [1] that I had the opportunity to collaborate with.

[1] Research domains:

*Epidemic - COVID-19

*Financial - Supply Chains

*Cultural Heritage - Museum Collections

*Environment - Cycle Plot

*Financial - Fraud Analysis

*Migration - Vienna Internal Data

*Biology - Phenology

*Sports - Soccer

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations? hl=en&user=Pmr3clYAAAAJ

Experience

Vienna University of Technology University Assistant at Centre for Visual Analytics Science and Technology (CVAST) April 2015 - April 2021 (6 years 1 month)

Wien, Austria

Main responsibilities:

- * perform research and develop concepts in the field of Data Science, Visual Analytics, and Interaction Design.
- * design new techniques and implement interactive prototypes
- * write scientific publications

- * review of scientific publications
- * participate in scientific and consulting projects
- * participate in writing research proposals
- * work within a creative, highly motivated, and international team
- * participate in teaching and supervision of student projects and theses

UFRGS

Scientific Researcher March 2013 - March 2015 (2 years 1 month) Porto Alegre, Brazil

Main responsibilities:

- * perform research and develop concepts in the field of Data Science, Visual Analytics, and Interaction Design
- * design new techniques and implement interactive prototypes
- * write scientific publications & research proposals
- * review of scientific publications
- * participate in scientific and consulting projects
- * teaching and supervising of student projects and theses

ADP

Software Developer January 2011 - December 2012 (2 years) Software developer in ACS Portal team.

Education

Technische Universität Wien

Ph.D., Computer Science, Data Visual Analytics · (2015 - 2021)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

Master's degree, Computer Science, Data Visual Analytic · (2013 - 2015)

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2009 - 2012)